Ten
Nine eight
9、8
Seven six
7、6
Five four
5、4
Three two
3、2
One
菲律宾，1999年
Dr.Serizawa?
是芹泽博士吗？
Jerry boyd I'm warning you it's a mess
我是杰瑞·博伊德我特意来提醒您
It's just a total mess
情况非常糟糕
Monarch sent me in this morning
今早我奉命来查看情况
Took a look around but I told them we needed you
不过我告诉他们我们需要你
They picked up a radiation pocket out here last month
上个月矿工发现了放射性矿囊
They got excited thinking they had a uranium deposit
他们很激动以为找到了铀矿床
They started stacking up the heavy machinery and then
于是开始往这里调集大型机械
Well,the valley floor collapsed
可是，谷底突然发生塌陷
Into a cavern below
掉进了地下洞穴
Just dropped away Just gone
就这么全都没了什么都不见了
Best guess right now is about 40 miners went down with it
目前初步统计有40名矿工被埋在下面，要进去吗？
This way
这边
When they first discovered this pocket the radiation levels were only half as strong
他们刚发现放射性矿囊的时候辐射强度只有现在的一半
It's almost as if contact with the outside air
好像是一接触到外面的空气
Started catalyzing something
就加速了某种反应的进程
Some kind of fossils right?
这是某种化石，对吗？
I've been digging holes for 30 years I've never seen anything like it
我挖矿三十多年了还从来没有见过这样的东西
Oh my god is it possible?
我的上帝这怎么可能
Is it him?
会是它吗？
No
不
This is much older
这比它可老多了
Hey guys You gotta see this
喂！伙计们快来看这个
What is it?
这是什么？
Some kind of egg?
是某种蛋吗？
A dormant spore?
休眠中的孢子？
The bones are fossilized
骨骼已经变成了化石
But this formation seems to be perfectly preserved
但这个却没有这个构造却被完整地保留下来
This one looks broken
这个看上去破了
It's like something came out of it
好像有东西出来过
占几拉镇，日本
I'll get it It's probably for me
我来接可能是找我的
喂！
No takashi
不！明石先生
No takashi just listen to me for a second
不！明石先生你先听我说
I'm asking for the meeting because if I have to shut the reactor down
我请求面谈是因为我必须关闭核反应堆
You're not gonna want to read about it in a memo
我不希望你在事后才知道
I've been following these tremors since they started in the philippines
我从一开始的菲律宾一直在跟踪研究这些震动
And now they're in our own backyard
现在都震到家门口了
No no no hayato says
不！不！不！不！隼人说
I need to go through you about this
我需要先跟你沟通一下
Look i'm just trying to follow the protocols set forth by the company
听着，我只是在努力遵守公司规章制度
That's all It's my job
没有别的意思这是我的工作
He's awake
他醒了
Oh I know He got up early
噢！我知道他早就醒了
What are we gonna do?
我们怎么做？
Get dressed I'll figure it out
穿好衣服我来想办法
Okay? Okay
好吗？好吧
Later dad
再见！爸爸
With all due respect takashi and honor
我很尊敬你明石先生，敬佩你
Respect and honor with all of that
我是发自内心地敬重你的
I'm an engineer I don't like unexplained frequency patterning
可作为工程师我不能容忍在我负责的范围内
Near a plant where I'm responsible I need a meeting Make it happen
存在无法解释的波段结构我需要当面谈
Joe speaking in japanese
好了，好的，好的，希望你能理解
Bye Mom!
妈妈再见！
He made you a sign
他给你做了个徽章
What? your birthday sign
噢？你的生日徽章
He worked so hard oh god
花了很多心思，噢！上帝
I'm gonna come home early
我今天早点儿回家
I'll take the car and pick him up
先开车接他
And we can get a proper cake okay?
然后去买生日蛋糕，怎么样？
Listen I need to know
听着我要知道
That it's not the sensors okay?
这不是传感器的问题，懂吗？
I can't be calling this meeting and look like the American maniac
我不能在会议上表现得像个美国疯子
So when we get there
所以到那儿以后
Don't even bother coming up Just grab a team and go down to Level 5.
先别急着上楼带人去地下五层看看
You're not a maniac
你不是疯子
I mean you are just not about this
我是说你在这个问题上没疯
Must be something we're not thinking of
我们肯定忽视了什么
Happy birthday
生日快乐
What? Is it?
什么？难道？
Yes it is
对！没错
Oh I forgot all about it
噢！我都忘了
Happy birthday thank you!
生日快乐！谢谢
I should have a birthday more often
最好天天过生日
What is this? seismic anomaly
这是什么？地震波异常
This graph is minutes
时间单位是分钟
X Is minutes not days this is now
X轴是分钟不是天数，这儿刚出来的
Wait hold on Seismic activity?
等等！等一下地震波异常
Seismic? you're talking about earthquakes?
你的意思是说？这是地震的前兆？
No earthquakes are random jagged
不！地震波是杂乱的锯齿状
This is consistent increasing
这个是有规律的在增强
This is a pattern
波形明显
All right let's make this quick
都好了我们动作快点
Takash what the hell is going on?
明石，到底是怎么回事？
Have you seen this?
这个你看了吗？
Yeah maybe not such good time for a meeting
看了，也许现在不是开会的时候
What's the source?
震源是什么？
Where's the epicenter?
震中在哪里？
We don't know
还不知道
But it keeps getting stronger
但是一直在持续增强
It's gotta be centered somewhere
肯定能找到中心点
Hayato
隼人
No one else is reporting it
没有人汇报过
We are contacting every other plant in the Kanto region Tokai Fujiyama
我们正在跟中州东海和富士山所有的核电站联络
They're unaffected
他们没受影响
But my guess is these readings are just aftershocks from the Philippine earthquake
不过我认为我们监测到的应该是菲律宾的地震余震
Are we at full function?
是在满负荷工作吗？
Yes we are
是的，没错
But perhaps we should be drawing down to be safe
也许为了安全起见应该下调能量值
Take us offline
必须马上关闭
Now Joe do it!
不，乔！我们应该...快点儿
Now wind it down
彻底关闭
Sandra
桑德拉
Sandra are you there?
桑德拉你在吗？
We're turning back
我们回去吧
Let's go
都快点儿
Oh my god
噢！上帝啊
Joe are you there?
乔！你在吗？
Joe there's been a breach
乔！要发生泄漏了
We're heading back to the containment seal
我们要回到封闭舱去
Listen you need to get out of there
桑德拉听我说，你们马上离开那儿
If there's been a reactor breach you won't last five minutes
如果核泄漏即使穿着隔离服
With or without the suits
你们也活不过5分钟
Do you hear me?
听见了吗？
I hear you! we're coming
我听见了我们来了
I'll meet them there myself
我自己下去迎他们
Put the safety doors on manual override
把安全门调成手动控制
I cannot do that!
我不能那么干
Keep the doors open my wife is still in there
先别关门我妻子在里面
Come on
快！
Let's go!
大家快点儿！
Tell me this door's on manual
明石，启动手动控制了吗？
Yeah but we are starting to breach!
是的乔，但是已经开始泄漏了
I'm here Soon as they're through i'll seal it
我在这儿他们到达后我来关闭
Sandra can you
桑德拉亲爱的
Hear me? i'm at the door
听见了吗？
Sandra?
我在这里桑德拉
Sandra i'm waiting for you
桑德拉我在等你
I'm at the checkpoint
我在安全门这里
But you have to run as fast as you can
但你要快跑越快越好
I am!
我知道
Kenji Kenji
铃木，铃木
We need to go!
我们快走
Joe!
乔！关闭安全门
明石，他们还没出来
Close the door!
封闭通道
Seal the corridor or the whole city will be exposed
否则整座城市都会被炸毁的
Sandra?
桑德拉
Joe? Joe can you hear me? Yes
乔、乔？能听见吗？听见了
Are you there?
乔，你在吗？
Sandra sandra i'm here can you hear me?
桑德拉，我在你听见了吗？
Yeah
是的
Joe it's too late
乔，太晚了
We're not coming
我们回不去了
No don't say that don't you say that
别这么说不要这么说
Run as hard as you can honey
你们快跑我等你们
Joe you have to close the door
乔，你必须关上安全门
You have to live for our son
你要为我们的儿子活下去
Joe seal the door now oh my god
乔，封死门，快！上帝啊
Five seconds Four seconds
5、4
I'm sorry
对不起
Take care of Ford
照顾好福特
Be a good father
做个好爸爸
I Will
我会的
We didn't make it
告诉他我爱他
情况紧急
Let's go out!
大家快出去
Hurry come on ford
福特，福特，快点儿
15年后
On your feet!
起立
You got family waiting for you?
有人在家等你吗？
I hope so
但愿吧
How long you been away?
你离家多久了？
Fourteen months
十四个月
Take it slow
慢慢来吧
It's the one thing they don't train you for
就当是一个新的挑战
All right! Let's go!
好了！我们走
I can't tell you can I see it?
就不告诉你，我能看看吗？
旧金山
Don't let him see don't let him see
别让他看别让他看
Whoa oh my god
噢，我的天呐
It's a welcome home cake my god Look at that
欢迎你回家，天呐快看呐！
That's you
那个是你
And that's me what's it say?
另外那个是我，写的是什么？
"Welcome home Daddy"
欢迎爸爸回家
Daddy's home
爸爸回家
Daddy's home cake every night
爸爸回家，每晚都有蛋糕
Yeah that's not happening daddy's home equals
是啊看把你美的，爸爸回家
Cake every night
等于每晚都有蛋糕
How did you manage to get chocolate on your eyeball?
天呐！你怎么把巧克力吃到眼睛上了
Daddy did it
是爸爸弄的
I can't sleep with you making all this noise
你再闹我就不跟你一块睡了
Come on let's get you into bed
来，把被子盖上
Okay big man
睡吧大个子
Time to hit the rack
要服从命令
Dad?
爸爸
Yeah?
干嘛？
Are you still gonna be here tomorrow?
你明天还会在这儿吗？
Yeah
当然！
Come on let's get some sleep
好了，快睡吧
Turns around nose to-nose he says at ease lieutenant
转过来，就这么脸对脸别紧张海军中尉
God I missed your laugh
我天天都在想你
I missed you
我也想你
I should get that no it could be work
我得接一下可能是医院的
I need to get that you don't need to come on
我接一下，别管它！
Hello?
你好？
Yeah this is mrs Brody
对！没错我是布罗迪太太
Tell him you're busy tending to your husband's needs
告诉他，你正忙着满足丈夫的需要呢
Yeah he's my husband
对！他是我丈夫
Tell them we're not gonna buy it
告诉他我们什么都不买
Yes sir could you just hold on one moment?
好的先生，你能等我一下吗？
It's the consulate
领事馆打来的
Joe's been arrested in japan
乔在日本被逮捕了
Elle I can't find my pants
艾丽我裤子在哪儿
They're in the other drawer
在那个抽屉里
So why was he trespassing in the quarantine zone?
他为什么会去擅闯隔离区呢？
Why do you think?
还能为什么？
The lone crusader for the truth
寻找真相的孤胆英雄
All his crackpot cuckoo theories
简直没法理解他那些疯狂的理论
Your father is a good man He just needs your help right now
你父亲是个好人他现在需要你的帮助
Ford he's lost everything
福特，他已经什么都没有了
Yeah so did I but you know what? i got over it
对，我不也是一样？但至少我挺过来了
Right I can see that
是啊看得出来
I'm sorry it's just
对不起！只是...
Every time I let him in close he always tries to drag me back
每次我一跟他亲近他就想把我拉回到过去
And I can't I can't put our family through that
我做不到我不能让我的家人再受伤害
Well he is your family
可他也是你的家人
Hey come here
嗨！过来
You know you're only gonna be gone for a few days right?
你只不过就离开几天而已，对吗？
And then you are gonna come back to me
然后就马上回到我的身边
Yeah yeah
对，对
It's not the end of the world
又不是世界末日
东京
I don't get many visitors
我这儿不常有人来
Clearly
看出来了
This is you here
你就睡这儿吧
Even uh Ph.D.'s
即使是博士
Don't get much teaching english as a second language
做英语外教也赚不了多少钱
Here we go
收拾好了
And a towel
这毛巾是干净的
All right
好吧
So
那么
How's the bomb business?
炸弹生意怎么样？
It must be a growth area these days
这年头这生意肯定红火
It's called "explosive ordnance disposal"
我的工作叫做爆炸物处理
My job isn't dropping bombs
我们不是投掷炸弹
It's stopping them
而是阻止
Dad hey
爸爸，嗨！
How's elle doing?
艾丽还好吧？
And sam oh my god he must be
还有萨姆我的天呐
What? three? three and a half?
他现在多大了？三岁？还是三岁半？
He's almost 5.
快五岁了
I thought you were over this
还以为你想通了呢
"Echolocation?"
回波定位法
Oh hey "Parasitic communication"
嗨！种群间的沟通
Please don't if you don't mind
不好意思别动这些
I have everything the way I like it
弄乱了我就找不到了
I'm just I'm studying bioacoustics
噢，我正在学习生物声学
What were you doing going back there?
你回到那地方去干什么去
This trespassing stuff that was bull，you broke the law
所谓的非法入侵根本就是胡说八道，你犯了法
I was trying to get back to our old house
我只是想回到我以前住的房子
In a quarantine zone，Precisely
可房子在隔离区，对！没错
The new readings are exactly like they were on that day
新的数据跟那天一模一样
And I can prove it to you
我可以证明给你看
With a little luck if I can get back to the house
如果够走运让我回到那个房子
I can show you and the world this was not from a natural disaster This was
我可以证明给你和全世界这不是自然灾害造成的不是地震波异常
Dad!
爸爸
Your mom's out there，ford
你妈妈留在了那里，福特
To me
对我来说
She'll always be there
她一直在那里
They evacuated us so quickly
当初撤离得太仓促
I don't even have a picture of her
甚至连她的照片都没留下
This has to stop
你不能再这样了
You know I did everything I could
你知道我已经尽力了
You know that，right?
你知道，对吗？
Let me take you home
跟我回家吧
Come home with me
我们一起回家
I got a little boy who's desperate to see his grandpa
家里有个男孩在盼着他的爷爷
We can leave tomorrow
我们明天就动身
先生，大致情况就是这样
好的非常感谢
具体的细节，还是见面再说吧
那好吧，我尽快赶到那里
如果你要过来，最好快点儿，再见
好的！再见，非常感谢
What are you doing?
你在干嘛？
I'm heading back out there，Ford
我得再去那儿一次，福特
One hour in and out，no i don't think so
一个小时就能回来，不！我不同意你去
I have to go!
我必须去
I came back here and wasted six years
我回到这里花了整整六年的时间
Staring through that barbed wire
望着那片铁丝网
Thinking it was a military mistake
那可能是场军事事故
Or some horrible design flaw they were covering up
或者是因为设计上大有失误所以他们要掩盖真相
One day
有一天
I met a guy who runs a cargo boat offshore
我遇见一个在近海跑船运的人
Every day he goes right past the reactor site
每天他都会经过反应堆那里所以
He places a couple frequency monitors on buoys for me so
我让他替我在浮标上放置了频率监测器，所以
Two weeks ago
两周前
I check this thing like every other day just for the kick.
我因为每隔一天都会检查反正闲着也是闲着
Two weeks ago I'm tuning in
两周前调节频率时
And oh my god
我的天呐
There it is
收到了
Whatever "it" is that's in there
不管到底是什么它就在那儿
Whatever it is they're guarding so carefully
就是他们小心翼翼把守着的东西
Started talking again
这东西又说话了
And I mean talking
我听见它在说话
I have to go back to our house
我必须回到我们的房子
I need my old disks if they're still there
去找回我的磁盘如果还在的话
I need the data to be able to prove a baseline here
里面的数据跟这次的数据对比就能证明
That this isn't a fantasy that I'm not what you think I am
我的观点不是凭空想象我不是你想的那样
I'm gonna find the truth
我会找到真相的
And end this
了断这一切
Whatever it takes
无论代价是什么
Why can't you just let it rest?
为什么你就不肯罢手呢？
Because I sent her down there son
是我让你妈妈下去的
This wasn't just a reactor meltdown
事故的原因绝没有那么简单
I don't wanna hear this
我不想再听下去了
I know，I know you don't
我知道，知道你不想听
But you can't keep running away
但你不能永远回避问题
And son you can't bury this in the past
不能把这一切跟过去一起埋葬
What spooked them?
它们在怕什么？
Dad，come on Let's go. It's only another two blocks
爸爸，快点儿走吧还有两个街区
Dad!
爸爸
Are we going home or what?
我们还去不去了？
Whoa Hey，what are you doing?
喂，你在干什么？
Dad?
爸爸
It's clean
很干净
I knew it
我就知道
The radiation in this place should be lethal but there's nothing
这儿的辐射指数本该是致命的但却什么都没有
Thank god
感谢上帝
Are they rebuilding the plant?
他们是要重建核电站？
I don't know I haven't seen
不知道，我没看见
五号车抓到入侵者，请求带往本部
你们在干什么？不许动，你们知道后果吗？
占几拉
抓到入侵者
Ten seconds，ten seconds
10秒，10秒
准备放水，拜托了快点呼叫增援
Seven-point-two seconds and getting stronger
7.2秒越来越强烈
We're trending exponentially
以指数趋势增长
That's our new curve
这是新高
Jesus，it's worse than we thought
上帝，比想象的还糟
Excuse me Dr.Serizawa?
打扰一下芹泽博士
Two men were just arrested in the q-zone
刚刚抓到两名入侵者
We've got bigger problems here Have Dr.Graham take a look
没看见正忙着吗让格雷厄姆博士处理吧
She did sir She sent me
她在处理让通知你们
One of them says he used to work here doctor
有个人说他以前在这里工作过
You are not fooling anybody
你不要再撒谎了
When you say that what happened 15 years ago
十五年前你跟大家说这只是自然灾害，对吗？
Found these disks in his bag was a natural disaster
在他包里发现了这些磁盘和资料
Not sure what to make of them，Not an earthquake
不知道该怎么处理，那不是地震
It wasn't a typhoon
那也不是台风
Okay? So stop
不是吗？别费劲了
Look I'm tired of talking to you about this
我懒得再跟你浪费口舌
I want my son
我要见我儿子
I wanna see my son I wanna know that he's all right
我要见我的儿子要确保他没事
This guy，this guy knows
这家伙，这家伙知道
He knows where he is
知道我儿子在哪儿
Speaks in japanese
我要见我的儿子
I want my son
我要见我儿子
And I want my bag and disks
把我的包和磁盘还给我
And I wanna talk to somebody in charge，not you No not you
我要跟这里的负责人说话不跟你说不是你，不不不不跟你说
I'm done talking to you
再也不想跟你废话了
All right?
行了吗？
You're looking at me right now like I'm in a fish tank，right?
我知道你们正在看着我就像我在水族箱里一样，对吗？
Fine Because I know what happened here
无所谓因为我知道这里发生过什么
And you keep telling everybody that this place is a death zone
可你们对外却说这里是死亡地带
But it's not，You're lying
但事实不是这样，你们在撒谎
Because what's really happening
因为事情的真相就是
Is that you're hiding something out there
你们在这里藏匿着什么东西
I'm right aren't I?
我说对了不是吗？
My wife died here!
我妻子就死在这儿
Something killed my wife
她是被杀死在这儿的
And I have a right to know!
我有权利知道
I deserve answers!
我有权利知道真相
All these items they were found on him
这些磁盘和资料我检查过了
And the date Look 15 years ago
日期是十五年前的
I thought all of the data from that day was lost
我以为那天所有的数据都已被毁了
I guess not
看来不是
You see?
看吧
看呐
There it is again
又出现了
That is not a transformer malfunction
这可不是变压器发生故障
That is an electromagnetic pulse
这绝对是一种电磁脉冲
It affects everything electrical for miles and miles
好几英里之内一切电器都会受到影响
And it is happening again
现在又发生了
This is what caused everything in the first place
这也就是最初发生事故的原因
Don't you see that?
你们还不明白吗？
And it is gonna send us back to the Stone age
会把我们直接送回石器时代
You have no idea what's coming
我们就要大难临头了
Pulses are seconds apart
脉冲几秒一次
They're getting stronger It's affecting the power grid
而且越来越强会影响到电网
Any radiation leakage?
有辐射泄漏迹象吗？
Gamma levels are still zero
伽玛读数仍然为零
It sucked all three reactors dry
把三个反应堆都吸干了
退后 退后
It's done feeding
它结束进食了
What's this?
这是什么？
It's the same pattern
上帝！同样的波形
Fifteen years ago it's what caused the meltdown
十五年前它就是罪魁祸首
An electromagnetic pulse
电磁脉冲是个手段
That's what it's building to Converting all that radiation
它在吸收能量吸光所有辐射
Until it hatches
直到破茧而出
We have to shut down
不能再继续了
Secure the grid
撤出第一区
Wildfire protocols
启动紧急预案
All personnel clear the first perimeter immediately!
所有人员立即撤出第一区，马上！
这不是演习！所有无关人员请立即前往避难所
抓到的入侵者怎么处置
What's going on? Hey where you going?
嗨，你去哪儿？
Grid's secure
已经就绪
Kill it
动手吧
All readings are flatlined
波形成直线了
Get a visual
派人看看
Jesus check the grid hit us with an emp
天呐，电网被电磁脉冲攻击
We're losing power!
电全断了！
Get the backup generators online，working on it
启动备用发电机，已经启动
That pulse fried every circuit
但是脉冲线路瘫痪
Check the cage，trying the backup generators
检查线路，再试备用发电机
Here we go
好了
Everybody out!
大家快出去
Now!
快
Hey! Let me out，Hey!
嗨！放我出去，嗨！
No！No！wait！
不，不，等等！
Stop!
等等
Ford!
福特！
Dad!
爸爸!
It was unlike anything i've ever experienced before
这种现象以前从没经历过的
Yeah，it's uh Ford Brody
对！是福特·布罗迪
Japan to San Francisco
从日本飞旧金山
Okay，could I at least if you could let me leave you my cell
好，那我能不能给您留下我的手机号码
Hello?
喂
Damn it!
该死的
I'm sorry
我很抱歉
Hey it's okay
没事的
It's okay，Daddy's gonna be okay
没事的！爸爸不会有事的
Daddy's gonna be okay
不会有事的
This area is now under naval military jurisdiction
这个区域现在由军队接管
All personnel must report to the duty officer for debriefing
如有疑问请与当值军官联系
Dr.Serizawa!
芹泽博士！
Dr.Serizawa
Captain russell hampton
我是罗素·汉普顿
Glad to find you sir
很高兴找到你
I've been briefed on your work with operation monarch
我对你正在参与的帝王计划有所了解
Now I'm told your organization has situational awareness
我被告知你的机构对未知生物的研究
Of our unidentified creature
已经有了突破性的进展
Is that right?
是这样吗？
We are now taking over
我是来通知你
Operational authority from monarch
帝王计划现在已经被我们军方接管了
So i'm gonna need you to come with me
所以得请你跟我走一趟
Is there any other personnel you need?
你需要什么人协助你吗？
They'll take care of you
没事的爸爸
I'll be right next to you
我会一直陪着你
Okay
好的
Them
那两个
Let's get his vitals
好了检查他的生命体征
Dad Dad，Radial pulse is weak I'm counting 125.
爸爸，爸爸！脉搏很微弱心率每分钟125
It's okay
没事的
You were right
你是对的
I'm sorry
我很抱歉
Go home to your family
回到家人身边
You keep them safe
保证他们的安全
Okay? Okay
好吗？好的
Whatever it takes
无论发生什么
Whatever it ta
保护他们
Hey stay with me
爸爸别睡
Dad?
爸爸
Dad，radial pulse is weaker Barely feel it
爸爸，脉搏在变弱快感觉不到了
We're losing him
他要不行了
Joe，can you hear me? He's going into A-fib
乔，能听见吗？开始房颤了
Give me another epi one milligram and 4O units of vasopressin
再来1000毫克肾上腺素40个单位的加压素
Stay with us come on joe，hang in there buddy
千万别睡坚持住乔，加油伙计
美国海军
“萨拉托加号航空母舰”
This is our needle in a haystack people
这简直就是在大海捞针
Muto
穆托
Massive unidentified terrestrial organism
未明种类的巨型陆生生物
It is however no longer terrestrial It is airborne
但是现在不再是陆生了它会飞了
The world still thinks this was an earthquake
现在全世界仍然以为这是一场地震
And it would be preferable that that remain so
那我们最好的办法就是保持现状
Before we lost sight it was headed east across the Pacific
在消失之前它穿过太平洋往东面去了
And had emitted enough emp disruption
并发射出破坏力很强的电磁脉冲波
To create havoc with our radar and satellite feeds
我们的雷达和卫星传送系统
And reduce us for the moment
都受到了严重的干扰
To a strictly visual pursuit
暂时只有视频可以追踪到
I emphasize "for the moment"
我特别强调，暂时
Because we will get on our game
是因为我们很快会恢复
And we will find this thing
一定会找到这东西
It is imperative that we do so
这也是我们的职责所在
Captain I want any and all search options on this table asap
请把所有的搜寻方案尽快报上来
Yes，sir
是长官
Dr.Serizawa
芹泽博士
Admiral william stenz
我是威廉姆·斯坦兹
Nice to meet you，glad to have you on board
很高兴认识你，欢迎加入我们
Sensei
老师
Excuse me
抱歉
Authorities issued a statement，brody's dead
尽管死亡人数仍在增加，他死了
claiming the nuclear contamination
当局发布了一份声明称
Is at no risk of spreading even as the death toll rises
核污染并没有扩散
Lieutenant Brody?
布罗迪中尉
Dr.Serizawa
芹泽博士
My condolences
请您节哀
We are deeply sorry for your loss lieutenant
您父亲的事我们很遗憾
But I'm afraid we need your help
但我们还是需要您的帮助
This is the USS Nautilus
这是美国海军鹦鹉螺号
In 1954
1954年
The first time a nuclear submarine ever reached the lower depths
一艘核潜艇首次抵达了前所未有的深度
It awakened something
唤醒了某种生物
The americans first thought that it was the russians
美国人最先以为是俄国人干的
The russians thought that it was them
俄国人却以为是美国人
All those nuclear bomb tests in the '50s?
那些50年代进行的核弹试验
Not tests
不是试验
They were trying to kill it
他们是想杀死这东西
Him
就是它
An ancient alpha predator
一个远古的猎食者之王
Millions of years older than mankind
比人类还早几百万年
From an age when the Earth was 10 times more radioactive than today
当时地球上的放射性比现在强烈十倍
This animal and others like it
这只生物和它的同伴们
Consumed this radiation as a food source
将放射物当成食品来源食用
As the levels on the surface naturally subsided
随着地表的放射程度减弱
These creatures adapted to live deeper in the oceans
逐渐适应了生活在海洋深处
Further underground
地下更深处
Absorbing radiation from the planet's core
从星球的核心处获取放射物质
The organization we work for monarch
我们为之工作的机构帝王
Was established in the wake of this discovery
就是因为这个发现而建立的
A multinational coalition
一个秘密成立的
Formed in secrecy
多国联合机构
To search for him
去搜寻它
Study him
研究它
Learn everything we could
竭尽所能了解它
We call him
我们管它叫
Gojira
哥斯拉
The top of a primordial ecosystem
原始生态系统的最高统治者
A god for all intents and purposes
它是神，无论从什么角度看
A monster
一只怪兽
Fifteen years ago
十五年前
We found a fossil of another giant animal in the philippines
我们在菲律宾发现了另一头巨型动物的化石
Like gojira
很像哥斯拉
But this creature died long ago
但是它很久以前就死了
Killed by these
就是被它们杀死的
Parasitic spores
这是寄生孢子
One dormant but the other hatched
一个母体其余是孵化的
Catalyzed when a mining company unknowingly drilled into its tomb
一家矿产公司无意中挖到了它们的巢穴
The hatchling burrowed straight for the nearest source of radiation
孵化洞穴直指距离最近的放射源所在
Your father's power plant in janjira
你父亲所在的占几拉核电站
And cocooned there for 15 years
并在其中孵化了十五年
Absorbing its radioactive fuel to gestate to grow
利用那里的放射性燃料孕育成长
Until it hatched
直到今天
Like a butterfly into the creature you saw today
像蝴蝶一样孵化成你看到的东西
Wait，You knew about this?
等等，你早就知道这些？
This thing The whole time?
这个东西一直都知道
Why didn't you kill it when you had the chance?
那为什么有机会的时候没杀了它？
It was absorbing radiation from the reactors
它一直从反应堆里吸收放射性物质
We worried killing it
我们担心杀掉它
Might release that radiation and endanger millions
会释放出辐射造成严重的后果
That's why our mission was to contain it
所以我们的任务是控制它
To study its biology to understand it
研究它的生物性了解它
We knew the creature
我们知道这只生物
Was having an electrical effect on everything within a close proximity
对于距离它一定范围内的一切都具有电场效应
What we didn't know...
但不知道的是
Was that it could harness this same power
它在电磁脉冲袭击方面
In an Emp attack.
具有同样的能力
But your father did
但你父亲知道
He predicted it
他预测到了
What else did he say?
他还说过什么话吗？
Please try to remember mr brody
请好好想想布罗迪先生
Anything that would help us Anything at all
任何话可能都有用仔细想一想
I didn't listen
我没太在意
I just thought he was crazy
我觉得他是疯了
He was obsessed with all this
他沉迷于这些东西
Said something about an animal call
什么关于动物的交流
Something talking
什么东西在说话
Talking?
说话？
He said he was studying something
他说他在研究着什么
Echolocation
回波定位法
If the muto was talking that day
如果那天穆托说过话
Your father must have discovered something talking back
你父亲肯定发现了什么东西在回应
Check again，Yup
再查查，好的
Search for a response call
是什么在回应
This parasite
那东西
It's still out there
现在还在那儿蛰伏着
Where's it headed?
那接下来呢？
The muto is young
穆托很年轻
Growing
在生长
It will be looking for food
接下来它会寻找食物
Sources of radiation
寻找放射源
We're monitoring all known sites
我们在监测所有已知地点
But if we don't find it soon
但如果不能尽快找到
Then what?
会怎么样？
Nature has an order
大自然有一种能力
A power to restore balance
一种重建平衡的能力
I believe he is that power
我相信它就是那种能力
Sir，right now we're 50 miles from Hawaii
先生，我们目前离夏威夷50英里
This transport will take you there
这架飞机会带您过去
You're catching a commercial flight back to San Francisco
会有一架商务机带您返回旧金山
I'm gonna need you to brush your teeth
你该刷牙了
Disgusting those are terrible
太糟糕了嘴里好多细菌
We gotta brush them!
再不刷就该臭了
Citizens within a 100mile radius are being temporarily evacuated from the area
该地区方圆100英里范围内的居民已经被疏散
Hey，this is Elle You missed me Please leave a message
嗨！我是艾丽我现在不在，有事请留言
Elle
艾丽
I don't know what they're saying on the news
我不知道他们在新闻上是怎么说的
There was an accident in Japan
在日本发生了一起事故
Dad's gone
爸爸去世了
I'll explain when I see you
等见了面再细说
I'm headed to Hawaii I'm gonna catch a flight from there
我现在去夏威夷在那里搭机回去
I'll see you soon
很快能见面
Keep scrolling
继续往下
Near the end Before the emp
靠近最后在脉冲前面
There
在这儿
Something responded
有东西做出了回应
檀香山，夏威夷
Aloha，and welcome aboard
乘客您好！欢迎乘坐列车
The train will begin moving shortly
本次列车即将启动
For the comfort of others no smoking please thank you
为了他人着想请不要吸烟，谢谢
Please remember to stay clear of the automatic doors
为了您的安全请勿倚靠车门
Akio!
昭夫！
Mama!
妈妈！
Hey，hey
嗨！嗨
Mama!
妈妈！
I can't open it，Mama!
我打不开门，妈妈！
Look don't worry just wait there
别担心你们在这里等着
I'll bring him back
我会带他回来的
Okay?
好吗？
Mama! Hey，hey
妈妈！嗨，嗨
Mama!
妈妈！
Whoa Hey Whoa kid，Mama!
嗨！喂！孩子，妈妈
It's okay I'm gonna bring him back
放心，我会把他带回来的
All right I'm gonna set you down there
好了，我会把你送回去的
I'll get you back to your parents
带你去找爸爸妈妈
Okay?
好吗？
Here Is this what you want?
给，是不是很喜欢这个
Take good care of him for me
帮我好好照顾他
I better not miss my flight kid
但愿别耽误我赶飞机，孩子
Admiral，received an intel report
将军，我们收到一份情报
We lost track of a nuclear Akula 5O nautical miles northwest of Hawaii
在距离夏威夷50英里的海域有一艘俄罗斯核潜艇失踪
Could be the muto
可能是穆托干的
Just got word of a missing Russian sub in the North Pacific
收到消息俄罗斯潜艇在北太平洋失踪
Martinez?
马丁内兹
Aye special forces team sparta 1 is picking up a distress signal
是长官，特种部队斯巴达一号收到呼救信号
Northwest of diamond head on the island of oahu
在瓦胡岛钻石头西北方向
They're on the ground headed to the beacon
在地面向灯塔方向移动
On 5.23 north-northeast of the last beacon moving in on foot
最后一座灯塔东北偏北5.23搜索前进
Wanna tell me why we're looking
谁能告诉我为什么要在丛林里
For an Akula in the jungle?
寻找一艘俄罗斯潜艇吗？
Probably a glitch russians said they got a ping from this location
没准是错了俄罗斯人说在这里收到了信号
Hey，I got a reading It's right up ahead
嗨！我收到信号了就在正前方
Sparta 1 this is hawkeye
斯巴达一号我是鹰眼
We're getting the same ping off the transponder range 30 meters
我们收到了同样的信号范围30米
Looks like you're getting warm
看来你们接近了
What the hell?
这是什么呀？
Jesus
天呐
Oh my god
我的天呐
Guardian 3 we located your russian sub
三号守护人我们找到了俄罗斯潜艇
You're not gonna believe what else we found
还有个不可思议的发现
Holy shit
噢，我的上帝
It appears to be rising approximately 20 to 30 meters
能看到潜艇在树木上方二三十米高
Above the tree line
看得很清楚
We can't tell how wide it is
目测不出宽度
Cat's out of the bag doctor no more secrets
这秘密守不住了别想着保密了
Our highest priority now is safety
现在最重要的就是安全
There's close to a million people on that island
那岛上有一百万人
Get me eyes in the air
派人在空中盯着
We're picking up something else approaching from the pacific
还监测到不明物体从太平洋方向逼近
We need to check out that object
马上查明到底是什么？
General quarters
进入全面戒备
Bridge，this is the captain
舰桥，我是舰长
Where you going? up to the flight deck
你要去哪儿？去飞行甲板
I think he is coming
肯定是它来了
What are you doing?
你想干什么？
I have to see this
我得去看一下
Two charlie six we are circling the target go on your command
呼叫二号正在接近目标准备行动
Stand by got a visual bogey at my 12.
我已经发现目标12点方向
Be advised prepare to engage target
注意观察随时准备开火
We're getting movement own here
三号守护人我们这边有动静
Take cover!
注意隐蔽
Control i have no power I say again i've lost all
控制中心我失去了动力，重复我失去了动力
You all right?
没事吧？
You give it 10 seconds lights gonna come back on
10秒钟之后灯就会亮起来的
It's okay
别害怕
What was that? did you see that?
那是什么？你看见没有？
What is it?
那到底是什么？
Dad!
爸爸！
Zoe?
佐伊
Oh my god
天呐
Run run tsunami tsunami
快跑！快跑！是海啸
Target spotted offshore
亡命徒目标出现在海岸
Two knots due east of your position could be a second bogey
在你的方位以东两海里可能是另一只怪物
Anybody hurt? No.
有人受伤吗？没有
Anyone get an eyeball on the bogey? where is he!
谁看见它往哪儿去了？没看见
There you go
怎么样？
What did I tell you?
我就说吧
Get down!
蹲下
Let's go!
快走
Remember to stay
为了您的安全
Clear of the doors
请勿倚靠车门
Go go go!
快！快！快！
Target in sight two o'clock 300 meters
发现目标两点钟方向距离300米
We're on 6-X-O1 target confirmed
明白，我已经锁定目标
Jesus!
我的天呐
Can you tell us what happened?
到底发生了什么事情？
And everybody started running and screaming
所有人都开始奔跑尖叫
Sam please turn that TV off
萨姆把电视关了，行吗？
Hey did you hear me?
嗨！听见我说话了吗？
Off
关掉！
Come on sammy let's go
好了萨姆！走吧
Let's go it's bedtime
该睡觉了
Sammy，mommy look
萨姆，妈妈！看
Dinosaurs
大恐龙
Attention please Incoming patients
请注意，新进病人
Please proceed，excuse me
请到，抱歉！
Hi excuse me i'm sorry
嗨！抱歉打扰一下
This boy's been separated from his parents
这孩子跟父母走散了
Fill this out be with you
把这表填上
In just a minute
马上帮你解决
Hey，you got service on that cell phone?
你手机能打出去吗？
No，The pay phones don't even work
不，连公用电话都打不了
Akio! Akio!
昭夫！昭夫！
Mama! papa!
妈妈，爸爸
Corporal load up load up
全体上车，上车
Sergeant lieutenant brody U.S.navy
中士，我是海军中尉布罗迪
I need your help I'm trying to get to the mainland
现在需要你的帮助我要去内陆
It's your lucky day everything not tied down is moving east
今天算你走运所有运输工具都往东面去
Whoa is that where they're heading? yeah
它们往东跑了？对
I guess we're monster hunters now
我们现在是专业打怪兽的
Satellite transfer complete
卫星图像传送完毕
Simulations uploaded
模拟数据上传中
Satellite tracking continues
卫星追踪继续
Last satellite tracks predict the muto continuing due east
预计穆托会持续向东移动
All our models have the targets converging on the pacific coast
综合所有数据目标会在太平洋沿岸相遇
As of now it looks like Godzilla's still following the muto
目前看哥斯拉好像是在跟着它
He's hunting
它在狩猎
Have all vessels maintain current distance from target
让所有船舰跟目标保持目前的距离
And plot the speed and heading of these things
记录它们的速度和移动方向
I wanna know exactly when and where they'll make landfall
我需要知道它们准确的登陆时间和方位
Yes，sir
是长官
Doctor what did you mean by hunting?
你刚才说的狩猎是什么意思
You think it's chasing this muto?
你觉得它是在追逐穆托吗
But if the MUTO is his prey
如果穆托是它的目标猎物
The signal shows a call
这信号是在召唤
Why call up a predator? no it didn't
它干嘛自找麻烦？不
I think godzilla was only listening
把哥斯拉招来应该是个意外
The muto was calling something else
穆托肯定是在呼唤别的东西这是它的方式
The pattern
那波形
Focus the search on nevada
注意搜寻内华达州
Nevada? why would it go to nevada?
内华达？它怎么会去内华达？
It can't be It's impossible
这不可能绝不可能
What's impossible?
什么不可能？
There was another spore intact found in the Philippine mine
还有个完好无损的孢子体在菲律宾矿场找到的
But we vivisected it
但是我们把它解剖了
Ran every test on it for years
拿它做了好几年的实验
You confirmed it for yourself It was dormant
是你亲自确认的它是休眠的！
Maybe not anymore
也许现在不是了
This spore where is it now，doctor?
这个孢子现在在哪儿，博士？
It was highly radioactive It was disposed of
那东西辐射很大被摧毁了
The americans they took it
美国人被他们拿走了
Doctor，where is it?
博士，它在哪儿？
Where you put all your nuclear waste
在你们存放核废料的地方
Go go go!
快，快，快！
“尤卡山核废料储存库”
Right let's go!
好了开始吧
Give me a mark I eyeball on every vault
每一间库房都要仔细检查
Clear!
安全！
Clear! Clear!
安全！安全！
Clear!
安全！
Clear! Clear!
安全！安全！
Hey!
嗨
Is anyone in there?
里面有人吗？
Captain our UA vs have footage of the new muto
舰长，无人驾驶机拍到了新穆托的图像
Let's have a look
转到大屏幕上
Yes sir
是的长官
This is from five minutes ago
这是5分钟之前拍到的
My god
我的天呐
Playing all we have now
全部放一遍
It's almost 300 feet
近300英尺高
It's far bigger than the other one
比另一个大多了
But this one doesn't have any wings
但这只根本没有翅膀
A different sex?
是不同性别
A female
是雌性的
That's who he's been talking to
它是在召唤它
It must be a mating call
肯定是在求偶
The female remained dormant until the male matured
雌性保持休眠状态等待雄性成熟
Now they're seeking radiation
它们在寻找放射物质
To reproduce
以保障繁殖
Current tracking models indicate that all three targets are converging here
综合所有数据分析三个目标将会在这里会合
San francisco bay
旧金山海湾
But if we rig a nuclear warhead with a shielded timer put it on a boat and send it
如果把安装了防护计时器的核弹头安装在船上
2O miles out
让船距离海岸20英里之外
The radiation lures the mutos
用它的放射性来吸引穆托
And the mutos lure godzilla
穆托就会引来哥斯拉
And we detonate with minimal fallout risk to the city
然后引爆核弹这样对城市的损害最小
You can't be serious they feed on radiation
你在开玩笑吧它们就吃这东西
Correct that's why we use the bomb as bait
没错，所以才用核弹当诱饵
And kill them with the sheer force of the blast
爆炸会直接解决掉它们
This is crazy
简直是疯了
Doctor if you have any other ideas, I am all ears
博士，如果你还有别的办法我们洗耳恭听
Admiral
将军
Yes，doctor
博士，请讲！
Gojira may be the answer
哥斯拉也许就是答案
I believe
我相信
Be's here to restore balance
它来这儿就是为了这个
He can defeat them
它能战胜它们
And what We just stand by and watch?
就是说，我们只能袖手旁观？
I'm sorry doctor I can't take that risk
很抱歉博士，我不能冒这个险
Prep the warheads and get them moving to the coast
去准备核弹马上运往海岸
Yes sir，Yes sir
是长官！是长官！
Doctor I know you don't agree with this
我知道你不赞成这样做
But my first priority is to safeguard our citizens
但我首先考虑的是保护我们的市民
It's stopped
这表停了
Yes
是的
Eight-fifteen in the morning
上午8点15分
August 6 1945
1945年8月6号
Hiroshima
广岛
It was my father's
这是我父亲的
Heads up
都听着
We've got new destination new orders
刚接到命令我们有了新的目的地
Let's get geared up
马上调整装备
Hey tech sergeant
嗨！上士
What's the word?
什么情况？
Another one of those things popped up in Nevada sir
在内华达又发现了一个那种东西
孤松镇，加利福尼亚州
Okay everybody out
好了，大家下车吧
Can't fly any further
只能飞到这儿了
We're well in range of its emp
已经进入电磁脉冲的射程了
So from here on out it's on the ground or it's not at all
所以接下来的路程只能靠我们的两条腿了
Let's go!
走吧！
All right listen up!
好了都听着
This train and these weapons are headed to San Francisco
这列火车和这些武器将被运往旧金山
Anyone not part of this mission disembark now!
跟这项任务无关的人立即下车，快
Negative
这可不行
Can't do it sir
我不能同意
This is a high-risk mission
这是项高风险任务
That train is a national asset not amtrak
那列火车是国有资产不是美铁公司的
We good to go? just about
能走了吗？准备就绪
From the look of the casings on those minuteman lcbms
从这些民兵洲际弹道导弹的弹壳看
Guessing the digital module's been bypassed
我猜数码模块被彻底忽略了
And you're prepping for full analog retrofit
准备全面模拟改造吧
Is my jaw supposed to drop
这样我就会让你上车了
I get it You're Eod
我知道你是拆弹专家
I got my crew they know what they're doing
但我已经有人了他们知道怎么做
Aim the pointy end at the monsters right sarge?
尖头对准妖怪，军士长
When was the last time you let one of your guys put their fingers in a live bomb?
你的人到底多长时间没摸过炸弹了？
Look this is what I do
听着，我是干这个的
This is my job
这是我的工作
Master sergeant
军士长
My family's in the city
我家就在城里
Okay I need to get on that train
所以，我必须坐上那列火车
You heard the spokesman say
刚才发言人已经明确表示
That the White House has not ruled out the use of nuclear force
白宫并不排除动用核武的可能性
Sam your mom's gonna be right back
萨姆，你妈妈一会儿就过来
Emergency can I help you?
急救中心
Hello?
什么事？
Oh yeah just a sec.
好！稍等
Elle for you
艾丽，找你
Tell them I'll be there in a minute，elle
等一下马上来，艾丽
It's your husband
是你丈夫
Hello?
喂？
Elle
艾丽！
Ford?
福特？
Oh god
噢！上帝
You all right? how's sam?
你没事吧？萨姆呢？
I've been calling you everywhere
我一直在到处打电话找你
You okay'? I'm fine
你没事吧？我没事
I've got Sam with me
我和萨姆在一起
Great because I wanna get you both
太好了，我最担心的就是你们两个
Can't believe this is happening
简直是太可怕了
Ford
福特
You okay? Are you doing okay?
你没事吧？没什么事吧？
I'm okay Elle please don't worry
我没事艾丽，别担心我
Baby I'm so scared right now
亲爱的我好怕
I know
我知道
I'm gonna be at the hospital by sunrise
天亮的时候我会到医院
Then I'll get you and sam out
然后把你和萨姆接出来
Okay
好的
The military has a plan to deal with these things
军队有办法对付这些事情
I'm coming to get you both okay
我会来接你们俩的
Okay
好的
Can you please just hurry?
你能快点儿回来吗？
I Will
我会的
Elle
艾丽
I just wanted you to know that I love you!
我就是我就是想告诉你，我爱你！
I love you too!
我也爱你！
Just be safe
你小心点儿
I'll see you soon
等着我
Good to go let's move out
中尉快上车，出发了
As blackouts and electrical interference
受停电和电子干扰的区域正逐步向西扩大
Radiate farther and farther west citizens within 200 miles of the creature's current sphere of influence
怪物周围200英里范围内的居民受到严重影响
Are being urged to please find shelter
政府方面敦促大家尽快找到避难场所
Stay indoors and stay off the roads
不要出门不要停留在街道上
911 what's your emergency?
911您有什么事情？
Kids in the car
孩子还在车里
Debris going back about two miles
碎片波及大约两英里左右
This girl is not breathing
这女孩没有呼吸了
People that are hurt send somebody out here now
很多人受伤马上派人过来
Yes sir
明白
Yes warheads are on the move
弹头已经在路上了
I completely agree sir
我完全同意，先生
All right people Let's g
好了各位，开始吧！
I need to know the exact location of the mutos asap
我要第一时间知道穆托的确切位置
Aye
是长官
We're updating our models with the current tracking data now
正在更新最新的实时数据
Admiral
将军
Yes?
什么？
Please don't do this
请不要这么做
I understand your concerns doctor
我知道你在担心什么？博士
But I am sacrificing lives
为了把这些东西
Every minute trying to steer one of these things clear of population centers
引离人口密集地区每一分钟都有人送命
And now there are two more on the way
而现在又有两头正在赶来的路上
There are millions of lives at risk
几百万人危在旦夕
So all I want to know from you is...
所以我希望你能告诉我的是
Will it work and can they be killed?
会有用吗？杀得了它们吗
But we tried that before
可是我们以前试过了
We're talking dialable yield megatons not kilotons
我们可以调整当量百万吨级的不是千吨的
Nothing can withstand that blast
没什么能抵挡这种威力
Makes the bomb we tried to kill it with in '54 look like a firecracker
1954年用来杀它的只不过是支小鞭炮
Sergeant morales give me a hand
马勒斯中士帮个忙
I thought these nukes all detonated by remote control
我还以为这东西是遥控引爆的呢
The mutos knock out everything electric
穆托会干扰所有的电子设备
Including detonators
包括起爆器
Can't even get in range without these things going haywire
所以没等导弹进入射程就完全失灵了
But this
但是这个
This on the other hand
就是另一个选择
is old-school clockwork
老式的机械计时器
Takes a licking
轻轻一按
Keeps on ticking
马上开转
Holy shit
见鬼
Sergeant morales get down here with that radio
马勒斯中士带着无线电下来
On the double move move!
动作快点儿，快！
Snake eyes this is Bravo to November ls the bridge
蛇眼亡命徒呼叫十一月
Clear? over
桥梁安全吗？完毕
I say again
重复一遍
We got a train of vip cargo headed for the coast
一辆装满特需货物的火车驶向海岸线
Ls the bridge clear? over
桥梁安全吗？完毕
Snake eyes I need a sitrep
蛇眼收到请回答？
Are the tracks clear?
铁路安全吗？
We are at phase line yellow In the next 10 mikes we're advancing to phase line red
我们选择处于黄色警戒10分钟后将进入红色警戒
Secure or not? over
是否安全？完毕
You think it's intact?
你觉得桥还在？
Only one way to find out
只有一个办法能确定
You wanna take the top Sure
你负责上面，行
You check below sergeant morales you come with me
你负责下面，马勒斯中士跟着我
Shit
见鬼
Jesus
上帝
Jones you all right? Yeah I'm good
琼斯，你没事吧？我没事
The bridge is intact
桥梁完好无损
Bulldog this is eagle
牛头犬我是老鹰
All clear to move out over
可以行动！完毕
Roger that eagle
收到，老鹰
Let's go! Let's go people!
上车，大家上车！
Say again
请重复
I do not have a visual what is your position? over
我看不见你们在什么位置？完毕
Unreadable say again over
听不清楚请重复！完毕
Look out!
当心
Hit the deck
快卧倒
Help me turn it off man
快帮我关上它
Run!
跑
Move it run!
快跑！快！
Ford!
福特
He's going under
它下水了
Boats sound the collision alarm
舰队拉响碰撞警报
Frame 180
180幅
We're losing visual admiral
无法获取图像，将军
He's diving
它在潜水
Changing course and moving fast I've got him at 33 knots and picking up speed
改变航向移动迅速时速达到33节而且还在提速
He's gonna outrun us sir
比我们快多了
Watch the swinging
保持平稳
No swing!
不要晃
Hey!
嗨
Hold on!
等一下
Medic!
医务兵
They are insisting civilians make their way to the bart stations
海湾当地的市民们都在赶往当地的公交站
Bart stations are designated shelters，Wait
所有车站都已经成了临时避难所，等等
Wait these patients are my responsibility
等等，这些病人是我负责照顾的
Where are you taking them?
你要带他们去哪儿？
Across the bridges critical and children only
带他们出城只带重患和儿童
Shelters are gonna fill up fast
避难所马上就满了
Trust me they'll be safer outside the city
相信我他们去城外会更安全
I can take sam，No no no
我带着萨姆，不！不！
Ford's on his way
福特马上就到
If you change your mind the buses leave in 10 minutes
如果你改主意大巴10分钟后离开
Come on where are you ford?
福特，你在哪儿？
This way keep them moving!
这边，让他快点儿！
Let's go come on come on.
快！快！快！快！
Hey! where are they taking it?
嗨！要把它弄哪儿去？
Twenty miles offshore convergence point.
离海岸20英里的地方最佳聚集点
We're gonna lure them there
把它们引到那儿去
Three birds one stone
就能一石三鸟
Wait!
等等
Okay sammy
好了萨姆
Laura thank god
劳拉，感谢上帝
Sammy, you remember Laura she's mommy's work friend right?
萨姆记得劳拉吧妈妈的同事，记得吗？
She's gonna look after you for a little bit
她会替妈妈照顾你一小会儿
Daddy's gonna be here soon
爸爸马上来接你
And I'm gonna just come get you right after
妈妈也会很快来找你们的
I promise
我保证
Okay
好的
Come on sweetheart you're gonna come with me.
来吧宝贝儿，跟我在一起吧
Your mom's gonna stay and help
妈妈要留下照顾病人
Elle I'm gonna take care of him okay?
艾丽我会照顾好他的，放心
Say bye-bye mommy，Bye mommy
跟妈妈再见吧，再见妈妈
奥克兰市，加利福尼亚州
战术指挥部
I got him I got him
好了好了把他交给我
Just sit down here
来，过来坐下
Sit sit
坐下
Here
这儿
Did you lose consciousness?
你意识清醒吗？
I'm okay really i'm fine
我没事没事！真的
Sitrep please location of targets
报告情况目标现在的位置
Male muto was spotted 30 miles off the Farallon Islands
雄性穆托在靠近费拉隆群岛30英里的地方
Showing seismic activity to the east near livermore
东部靠近利弗莫尔的地区有地壳震动
Should be the female closing in
应该是雌性导致的
Where's godzilla?
哥斯拉在哪儿？
Last contact was five hours ago
最后一次记录是五小时之前的
Maintaining a bearing of 053 degrees descending below a depth of 10000 feet
方向053深度10000英尺
Be here within the hour
用不了一小时就能到达这里
Residents are trying to get out of the city any way they can
居民正在想尽一切办法撤离城市
There's still buses on that bridge
桥上还有好几辆大巴车
Come on!
来啊
Let's get those busses through let's go!
让大巴车快点儿开走，快点儿
We're not gonna stop the buses here
别把车停在这里
What?
什么？
I can't hear you
我听不见
Oh kids please be quiet
孩子们安静点儿别吵了
Move into position till you have a clean line of sight
移动到位直到你能瞄准
Portside two hundred meters
左舷200米处
Brace!
当心！
Hold your fire
先别开火
Holy shit
见鬼
Oh shit!
哦该死！
Hold on，Watch out!
等等，小心！
Fire! Fire! Fire!
开火！开火！开火！
Look out!
小心
Get down! get down in your seats!
趴在座位上，快！趴下！
Please get down!
快趴下！
Get out of the way Get out of the way
让开 快让开
Hey!
喂
Move out move move move!
快点儿！快！快！快！
Striker there's civilians on the bridge hold your fire
等等！别开火桥上有平民，别开火
Open fire!
快开火
Move! move!
闪开！闪开！
All right get in there，Prepare to arm the device
好了它来了，核弹发射准备
Ready you got it
就位
I'm all set
我准备好了
Arming keys!
插入钥匙
Three! two! one!
3、2、1
What the hell was that?
到底怎么回事？
Emf
脉冲干扰
Engine's stopped we lost power
引擎停了失去动力
You all right? Yeah
没事吧？没事
Fire! Incoming!
射击！它在那儿
Sam brody was checked into the oakland coliseum shelter an hour ago he is safe
萨姆·布罗迪一小时前被送到了奥克兰体育场避难所他很安全
No record of elle brody never made it out of the city
但是没有艾丽·布罗迪的记录应该还在城里
Well check again please
再查一遍，求你了
I told her to wait for me and I didn't make it
我让她等我，但是我没赶到
They are trying to get everyone downtown into subway shelters
很抱歉，滞留在城里的人都被转移到地铁避难所了
I'm sure your wife is fine
你太太不会有事的
Lieutenant brody
布罗迪中尉
I'm looking for Lieutenant brody
我找布罗迪中尉
Are you brody? Yes.
你是布罗迪吗？是的
Okay the male delivered the warhead to the center of downtown
好了都听着雄性怪物把核弹头弄到了市中心
That puts 100.000 civilians in the blast radius
这就意味着十万平民会在爆炸中受到辐射
We can't stop it remotely
但又无法远程解除
An analog timer has been installed
模拟定时器已经安装
The mutos are frying electronics within a five-mile bubble
靠近穆托五英里的范围内所有电子设备都将失灵
Means approaching from ground is not an option
就是说不可能从地面接近
That's why we'll be conducting a halo insertion
只能以高跳低开的方式空降
Jumping altitude Will be 30000 feet
跳伞高度将在30000英尺
We just skate to the top and drop
滑翔到正上方实施
Here and here
这儿，还有这儿
If you don't hit a skyscraper on the way meet at rally point charlie
如果没有撞到摩天大厦将在集结点C会合
Right here good?
就在这儿，明白吗？
Doctor any guesses where to look?
博士，你有什么好建议吗？
Underground
查找地下
If the mutos have spawned
如果穆托已经产卵
They'll be building a nest
它们肯定会筑巢
Captain
上尉
When you find the warhead
一旦找到了弹头
How long to disarm it?
多久能拆除？
Sir without seeing the analog mod I couldn't even guess
不知道模拟定时器的模式前我无法预测
Sixty seconds if I can access it
如果能找到它60秒足够
I retrofitted that device myself
我亲手改动过这个装置
Lieutenant Brody is our only EOD tech to survive the train attack
布罗迪中尉是火车事故中唯一幸存的拆弹专家
Well it sounds like we could use you
看来全指望你了
With all due respect
说句不吉利的话
If that doesn't work then what's plan b?
如果计划失败有备用方案吗？
The waterfront is located one klick downhill
海滩的位置就在山下一公里处
Get the bomb to the pier onto a boat
把它弄到码头上装上船
And as far away from the city as possible before it detonates
在爆炸之前开得离城市越远越好
Any questions?
还有问题吗？
Dismissed
解散吧
That's it Let's move
全体出发
Lieutenant
中尉
They've already been briefed
可能你还不知道
We have no extraction plan
这次没有接应计划
If you don't walk out you don't come back at all
如果没有及时撤离就永远留在那儿了
Sir i'll do whatever it takes
我会全力以赴的
This alpha predator of yours doctor
你的这个猎食者之王，博士
Do you really think he has a chance?
你觉得有获胜的可能吗？
The arrogance of man is thinking nature is in our control
人类总自以为是地认为控制了大自然
And not the other way around
恰好相反
Let them fight
让它们斗吧
Oh lord god we give thanks
万能的主啊感谢你
For the opportunities you have given us
给予我们这样的机会
Going together as comrades to defend our great nation
让我们共同为国家而战
We thank you for the time and service that you have given us together
感谢你给予我们一起服役的美好时光
Now as we are about to leave one another
我们即将奔赴战场
Let us have the strength
请给予我们力量
Take position take position
全体就位！全体就位！
I saw Team 1 move to the east
我看见第一小队往东去了
Two of our team members didn't make it I heard bits and pieces on the radio
我们小队损失两人无线电断断续续的
Snipers on the rooftop moving into position
狙击手已经在屋顶就位了
Here we go picking up the nuke
有了找到弹头了
Which way?
在哪儿？
One klick up the hill
在山上一公里
We found the warhead
我们找到弹头了
Let's go Up the hill this direction move
行动吧，这个方向我们走
Hey hey
嗨，嗨
Look
看
Let's move let's move
我们走，快走！
On my six
跟在我后面
Sarge get a look at this
中士你看看这个
We gotta get moving you got a signal yet?
继续前进，找到信号了吗？
I got it
找到了
It's down there
就在这下面
All right move move
行动
Grab a line!
小心点儿！
More light grazer
照亮点儿，格雷泽
Right clear out
当心点儿
Here we go
我们走
Whoa look out heads up
当心点儿我们走！
How much time we got left?
还剩多少时间？
We have 27 mikes
还剩27分钟
We gotta get this thing down
得把它弄下来
Move move i got you
好了我拿到了
Move it out move it out
闪开，闪开
Careful careful
好了，当心点儿
And down in three
一起放，3
Two
One
Let's get this cover off
把盖子打开
Lieutenant you're up
好了中尉，看你的了
It's not budging it's sealed shut
弄不动封死了
We need time to open it
需要时间打开它
We don't have time
没时间了快把它弄出去
We gotta get it on a boat
装上船运走
Grab the warhead! let's move
大家抓住弹头一起用力
Go!
走！
Easy
抬稳了
Easy easy
Move it out guys
钻过去，兄弟们
Lieutenant let's go!
中尉！快走！中尉
Watch out!
小心！
Lieutenant
中尉
Quick move move!
快，快，快，快走！
What the hell was that?
那是什么？
Holy shit! Did you see that?
见鬼，看见了吗？
This way
这边
Move let's go，Go! Move
快！快！快！快点儿，快！
Faster faster
快，再快点儿
Let's get this thing started
赶快发动引擎
Find the ignition sir
我找到引擎开关了
Give me that pack
把包给我
Here you go
给你
Come on come on hurry
拜托，快点儿！
Hurry it up let's go let's go!
快点儿！快上来！快！
She's coming for the bomb
它是奔核弹来的
Let's get this weapon secured
我来把核弹绑结实了
Come on
该死
该死的
Stay right here
待在这儿别动
Quiet!
安静
I hear some people come on
有声音在这儿
This one's in bad shape come on grab my hand we got you
抓住我的手我们来救你们了
Help him up help him up
拉他上来，拉上来！
Attention new arrivals
新到者请注意：...
Please proceed to the marked tables for registration
请前往设有标记的桌子注册登记
Let's make some room please!
请让条道，借过
Mary!
玛丽，玛丽
Daddy!
爸爸
Sam
萨姆
Mommy!
妈妈
Sammy?
萨姆
Mommy! Mommy!
妈妈，妈妈
Sweetpea
我的宝贝儿
Hi baby
宝贝儿
Oh baby
噢，宝贝儿